# THOMAS M. SEEBER

647-564-1358 • thomasmseeber@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/thomasseeber

#### **SUMMARY**

Data Analytics and Engineering Manager with 15+ years of software development, data analysis/engineering, and management experience. Led entrepreneurial strategies to find solutions utilizing bootstrap-level resources with a strong desire to understand the business and creating value positive solutions.

# **SKILLS**

Data	Development	Project Management
Statistical Analysis	Python	Requirements Analysis
Data Engineering (Azure)	Databricks / Spark	Costing / Budgeting
ETL with Data Modeling	Cloud Architecture (Azure / AWS)	Technical Scheduling
Neural Networks	GitHub/GitLab	ROI analysis
Machine Learning	CI/CD (Jenkins)	Agile / Scrum
Generative AI (Lang Chain / Rag)	JavaScript	Waterfall
Tableau / Power Bl	Linux Administration	Risk Mitigation
Data Cleaning	PHP	Vendor Management
SQL	HTML / CSS	Resource Allocation
Mongo (NoSQL)	API / RESTful	IT Asset Management

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Infrastructure Ontario, Remote

# Contract Data Science Manager (Mar 2024 – Present)

- Automate data collection and processing through ETL pipelines and data modeling increasing project and business analysis productivity by 33%.
- Assist and coordinate to delvelop a holistic data strategy with initial states improving the accuracy of Infrastructure Ontario's government queries by 19%.
- Benchmark statistical projection data for Ontario Governmental projects using machine learning to improve cost accuracy estimation by 25%.
- Elevate business unit data quality by streamlining and translating business processes into testable automated data testing removing 50% of data errors and reducing data noise by 23%.
- Direct and mentor two junior data scientists and data analysts on different strategic questions increasing executive satisfaction by 37%.

## University of Toronto, Remote

## Part-Time AI / Data Analytics / Data Science Instructor (Jun 2022 - Current)

- Lead data analytics and visualization virtual Zoom lectures and facilitated co-coding sessions, instructing on Python, Pandas, Spark/Databricks, AWS, Plotly, Tableau, SQL, Postgres, Git/GitHub, machine learning, Spark, JavaScript, Leaflet.js mapping, and Agile methodologies while driving net promoter scores above 50 with a team of 3 assistant instructors.
- Modify and deliver AI training programs including neural networks, generative AI, machine learning, data analysis, and business value generation increasing hire-rate by 50% over self-taught applicants.

Wuji Xuan Life Wellness, Remote

Senior Business and Data Consultant (Apr 2023 – Mar 2024)

Direct 3 teams

- Engineer ETL pipelines from SaaS platforms, including CMS/Web, Moodle/Teachable/LMS, Salesforce, JaneApp, QuickBooks, PostgreSQL, and Power BI into shared model on Databricks Unity Catalog to create better aligned KPIs creating a 29% increase in clients.
- Illustrate hidden customer patterns through data analysis and machine learning to establish more productive individual KPIs for each staff resulting in a 21.5% revenue increase per employee.
- Calculate financial models and predictive financial outcomes on different profit margins and re-price products based on market analysis, resulting in 20% improved revenue on retail sales.
- Persuade investors to increase equity holdings by 53% and boost board of directors' positive engagement by 31%.

## Stage 3 Talent, Remote

## Principal Data Consultant (May 2021 – Apr 2023)

- Champion teams of junior data analysts to create MVP products in client companies, producing over 500K in cost reduction or management realignment in client companies.
- Train in-house candidates over Zoom in Excel, AGILE methodologies, Python, Azure cloud solutions, data analytics, Databricks/Spark, Power BI, ETL, SQL, machine learning / AI, JavaScript, and design thinking resulting in a 99% placement or promotion rate.
- Collaborate with major companies to identify data analytics and data science skill gaps in current employees to design custom curriculum modules for in-house corporate upskilling, leading to over 1M in sales revenue.

U[tech] at Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Oh **Senior Web and Data Manager** (Feb 2018 – May 2021)

- Manage 3 Scrum teams of engineers to build and maintain university web sites with extensive 3rd part back-end data integration via ETL pipelines increasing website uptime by 25% and increasing user browse time on websites by 41%.
- Build ETL pipelines using Azure Data Factory, Power Query, PySpark, and Microsoft SQL, reducing end-of-year business unit effort by 75%.
- Designed and executed cost-effective vendor contracts that eliminated 25% of trouble tickets while managing technical tickets for all web teams reducing response time by 25%.

U[tech] at the School of Engineering, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Oh **Assistant Director of IT** (Feb 2012 – Feb 2018)

- Orchestrated 2 Scrum teams (5 direct engineer reports) and minimized costs by over 30K, including migrating critical assets into VMware Clusters and AWS.
- Harmonize technical on-site and vendor teams increasing the school of engineering's technical project success by 30%.
- Design Linux-based data pipelines between Microsoft SQL, Web applications, and research databases, reducing administrative work costs by 22%.

#### **EDUCATION**

Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Oh Master of Business Administration

DePaul University, Chicago, II Master's Degree of Computer Science

University of Illinois, Chicago, Il Bachelor's Degree in Psychology/English